I believe software is increasingly complex, but they need not be complicated.

I am a Human-Computer Interaction researcher currently working in the domain of media discovery & recommendation. My vision in general is to improve technology in general to make it more usable and especially accessibility. I generally approach this by first identifying a problem, hypothesizing solutions, and later testing with prototypes and user-studies. I find that this approach leverages my prior experience as a sysadmin and a technical team lead reasonably well.

EDUCATION

Masters of Computer Science · Baylor University · 2012–2014

THESIS: Giving the Users a Hand: Towards Touchless Hand Gestures for the Desktop

Bachelor of Computer Science \cdot Coventry University \cdot 2002–2005 Thesis: Remote PC Manipulation via PDA over Bluetooth

PUBLICATIONS

Reporting and Visualizing Fitts Law: Dataset, Tools and Methodologies Alvin Jude, Darren Guinness, and G. Michael Poor CHI '16 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems, (San Jose, CA), ACM (2016) http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2851581.2892364

Evaluating Item-Item Similarity Algorithms for Movies
Lucas Colucci, Prachi Doshi, Kun-Lin Lee, Jiajie Liang, Yin Lin, Ishan Vashishtha, Jia Zhang, and Alvin Jude
CHI '16 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems, (San Jose, CA), ACM (2016)
http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2851581.2892362

Models for Rested Touchless Gestural Interaction
Darren Guinness, Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Ashley Dover
SUI '15 ACM Symposium on Spatial User Interaction (Los Angeles, CA, USA), ACM (2015)
http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2788940.2788948

Modeling Mid-air Gestures With Spherical Coordinates
Darren Guinness, Andrew Seung, Ashley Dover, G. Michael Poor, and Alvin Jude
SUI '15 ACM Symposium on Spatial User Interaction (Los Angeles, CA, USA), ACM (2015)
http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2788940.2794356

Personal Space: User Defined Gesture Space for GUI Interaction.

Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Darren Guinness

CHI '14 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems, (Toronto, Canada), ACM (2014)

http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2559206.2581242

An Evaluation of Touchless Hand Gestural Interaction for Pointing Tasks with Preferred and Non-preferred Hands. Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Darren Guinness NordiCHI '14 Proceedings of the 8th Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction, (Helsinki, Finland), ACM (2014) http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2639189.2641207

Evaluating Multimodal Interaction with Gestures and Speech for Point and Select Tasks Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Darren Guinness NordiCHI '14 Proceedings of the 8th Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction (Helsinki, Finland), ACM (2014) http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2639189.2670267

Gestures with Speech for Hand-Impaired Persons
Darren Guinness, G. Michael Poor, and Alvin Jude
ASSETS '14 Proceedings of the 16th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility (New York, NY, USA), ACM (2014)
http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2661334.2661398

TECHNICAL SKILLS

 $Basic : Photoshop \cdot CSS_3 \cdot HTML_5 \cdot Ember.js \cdot Cassandra \cdot Nagios \cdot Qualitative \ Research \cdot Machine \ Learning \\ Intermediate : Python \cdot PHP_5 \cdot LATEX \cdot JQuery \cdot MySQL \cdot R \cdot Matlab \cdot Java \cdot Recommender \ Systems \cdot Personalisation \\ Advanced : User \ Experience (UX) \cdot Usability \ Testing \cdot Experimental \ Design \cdot Hypothesis \ Testing \cdot Gestural \ Interaction \\ Interaction \ Testing \cdot Systems \cdot Personalisation \ Testing \cdot Systems \cdot Systems \cdot Personalisation \ Testing \cdot Systems \cdot Systems \cdot Personalisation \ Testing \cdot Systems \cdot Systems$

OTHER SKILLS

COMMUNICATION : Former Malaysian Public Speaking Champion

Entrepreneurship : Baylor NewVenture 2014: Top-5 Finalist & 3rd place Elevator Pitch Martial Arts : Taekwondo (3rd Dan Black Belt), Karate, Aikido, MMA, Krav Maga

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ericsson · 2014–present · Researcher

Improved discovery of similar items by 38%. Led usability testing of new content discovery methods with a European partner. Currently also performs self-driven research for patent portfolio, a next-generation media delivery platform, and research collaboration with academic partners.

Reference: Nimish Radia · nimish.radia@ericsson.com

Baylor University · 2013–2014 · Research Assistant

Setup new HCI lab. Mentored juniors, established engineering procedures and infrastructure. Performed research in hand-gestural interaction and explored research options with other next-generation input devices. Overhauled software used for teaching database. Assisted in developing lab curriculum for teaching operating systems.

Reference: G. Michael Poor · michael poor@baylor.edu Reference: Greg Speegle · greg_speegle@baylor.edu

Self Employed · 2010–2012 · Technical Consultant

Served as an independent consultant for various project and companies including the following:

iOS Development, Agile Perspectives — Malaysia, 2011–2012

Performed R&D for use of Apple products in financial services. Built and deployed app for one international insurance corporation. Built app for a consumer-facing startup dealing in retail. Role included requirements gathering, feasibility studies, business case development, and technical consultation.

System Administration, CouchSurfing.org, 2010–2011

Deployed a cluster of static content servers with NGinX to reduce the load off the dynamic servers, which resulted in higher reliability or website as a whole. Tools of the trade included Puppet, Zabbix, HAProxy.

Aflexi · 2009–2010 · System Engineer

Aflexi was a CDN Software startup, and is currently a division of OnApp. Responsibilities were more DevOps involving backend development and system administration. Built a monitoring infrastructure from the ground up (traditionally done with Nagios) with custom scripts running on a specialized Collectd infrastructure; used to feed PowerDNS for DNS-based CDN routing. Tools of the trade included Puppet, Zabbix, Nagios, Reprepro, RRD.

Reference: Whei Wong · whei.wong@onapp.com

iMocha Consulting · 2007–2010 · Team Lead

Initially hired as a Junior Java Developer, but quickly tasked to build and run a LAMP team of up to 8 people, dealing mostly with financial institutions. Responsibilities included hiring, firing, and mentoring programmers, system administrators, system analysts, and interns, as well as requirements gathering from clients.

Reference: Koh Kok Wei kokwei@imocha.com.my

Sony Manufacturing · 2005–2007 · Engineer

Developed Linux-based software required for manufacturing. Developed a tool used to trace products which helped cut down tracability time from 2 working days to about 4 hours. Tools of the trade included MFC, VB.NET, PHP, Postgres, GTK.